Guide to the Franco Modigliani papers, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1970s-2003 RL.00905
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1936-2004 and undated, 58 boxes
  - Speeches and Lectures Subseries, 1966-2000, 7 boxes
    - 1998
      - Jan., Allegro moderato (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Dec. 6, L'intervista - Franco Modigliani: 'Occupazione, l'unica ricetta la flessibilitá' (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Dec. 7, L'Unitá interview (Box SL6)
    - 1999
      - Nov. 29, Modigliani: titoli gonfiati Wall Street vicina al crollo (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Nov., Passing the Chair (interview) (Box SL6)
      - Nov. 5-6 - Interviewed by W. Barnett and R. Solow, 1999-2000 (Box SL6)
      - Franco Modigliani, in Conversations with Leading Economists (Box SL6)
      - Franco Modigliani: Prima la gente, poi l'economia (interview) (Box SL6)
    - 2000
      - May 18, Evidence of Irrationality in Economic Response to Inflation (Box SL6)
      - June
        - Europa, la cura Modigliani (interview) (Box SL6)
        - An Interview with Franco Modigliani, in Macroeconomic Dynamics (Box SL6)
      - Oct. 30, The European Unemployment and the Prestige of the Central Bank (Box SL6)
      - Governo e sindacati dicono che va tutto benissimo, non cosi (Box SL6)
      - Science économique et dynamique du reél, in Mondialisation et sociéteés multi-culturelles (interview) (Box SL7)
    - 2001
      - Feb. 3, Modigliani: 'Incredibile che a Francoforte non abbassino le tassi' (interview) (Box SL7)
      - Sept. 15, Nobel Prize-Winning Economist France Modigliani on Risk...the Markets... and Saving Social Security (interview) (Box SL7)
      - Oct. 11, Social Security Shouldn't Be a Gamble (interview) (Box SL7)
      - Dec. 12, Nessun effetto domino, l'America latina reggerá (interview) (Box SL7)
      - The Journal Interview: Franco Modigliani, in Journal of Performance Management (Box SL7)
    - 2002
      - Mar. 26, Unidentified journal interview (Box SL7)
      - June 2, L'accordo e la strada giusta (Box SL7)
    - 2003
      - May 21, Modigliani: Rilanciate gli investimenti pubblici (Box SL7)
      - May 21, Processo all'Europa (interview) (Box SL7)
      - May 29, Ripresa a portata di mano (interview) (Box SL7)
      - June 6, Modigliani: niente piú alibi, ora investimenti e opera pubbliche (interview) (Box SL7)
      - June 19, Modigliani: ora si muova l'Europa, subito fondi pensione dell'Unione (interview) (Box SL7)
      - Aug. 14, Bene la flessibilitá ma ridurre le imposte non serve (interview) (Box SL7)
      - Sept. 25, Modigliani: 'Con quello show il premier ha disonorato il Paese' (interview) (Box SL7)
    - undated, Private Investment with Government Guarantees (Box SL7)
    - undated, Sviluppo economico e disoccupazione: dove e perché (Box SL7)
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1959-2003, bulk 1973-2003, 4 boxes
    Chiefly single typescripts and printed materials written by Modigliani's colleagues but not filed within Modigliani's research folders. Significant groups of writings exist in this subseries for Ezio Tarantelli and James Tobin, both of whom Modigliani collaborated with extensively. There are also a few pieces by family members - daughter, Leah Modigliani, and son, André Modigliani. The majority of writings by other economists are found in the Research and Writings Series; if they are not identified by name on the folder title, they can be located in most cases by consulting relevant subject topics and/or chronological period. Includes a folder of Nobel Prize articles honoring Modigliani; authors include Athanasios Koilakos, Lucio Izzo, G. P. Galli, Paul Samuelson, and Robert Merton. Organized alphabetically by last name or subject.
    - Andersen, Leonall (Box WO1)
    - Ando, Albert, 1973-2000, 5 folders (Box WO1)
    - Articles about Modigliani, 1982-1989 and undated (Box WO1)
    - Bach, G. L., 1961 (Box WO1)
    - Beaud and Dostaler, 1993 (Box WO1)
    - Becsi, Zsolt, 2001 Nov. (Box WO1)
    - Bertocco, Giancarlo, 1994 Feb. (Box WO1)
    - Bodie, Zvi, 1995 Oct. (Box WO1)
    - Dornbusch, Rudi, 1997 Feb. (Box WO1)
    - Drazen, Allan, 1978 Aug. (Box WO1)
    - Drèze, Jacques H., 1997-1998 (Box WO1)
    - Eisenmeyer, Robert, 1981 Oct. (Box WO1)
    - Fernandez, Pablo, 1989 (Box WO1)
    - Frankel, Jeffrey, 1986 Nov. 10 (Box WO1)
    - Gandhi, P. Jegadish, 1985 Dec. (Box WO1)
    - Garcia, C. B., 2003 June (Box WO1)
    - Ghimire, Ajaya, 1993 Dec. 8 (Box WO1)
    - Giambelluca, Jose Juan, 1985-1986 (Box WO1)
    - Gordon, Robert J., 1980 Nov. 6-7 (Box WO2)
    - Gorga, Carmine, 1983-1987, 2 folders (Box WO2)
    - Hartnett, William J., 2002-2003 (Box WO2)
    - Holland, Daniel and S. Stewart, 1978 May (Box WO2)
    - Jorgenson, Dale W. and B. Fraumeni, 1991 Oct. (Box WO2)
    - Koopmans, Tjalling, remarks in memory of J. Marschak, 1977 Dec. (Box WO2)
    - Kopcke, Richard, circa 1983 (Box WO2)
    - Kotlikoff, Lawrence, 1983 Dec. (Box WO2)
    - Kostoris, Fiorella Padoa-Schioppa, 1997-1998 (Box WO2)
    - Lindbeck, Assar, 1985 March (Box WO2)
    - Marschak, Jacob, 1974-1975 (Box WO2)
    - Mayer, Thomas, 1973-1988 (Box WO2)
    - Mendelson, Haim and Y. Amihud, 1980 (Box WO2)
    - Meyers, S. C. and G. A. Pogue, 1969 Nov. (Box WO2)
    - Modigliani, André, 1995-1996 (Box WO2)
    - Modigliani, Leah, 1997 Jan. 27 (Box WO2)
    - Nobel Prize articles honoring Modigliani, 1985-1987 (Box WO2)
    - Price, Robert and J.-C. Chouraqui, circa 1983 (Box WO2)
    - Ramiz, Antonio Argadoa, 1985-1986 (Box WO2)
    - Somermeyer, W. H., 1974 (Box WO2)
    - Steindel, Charles, 1977 (Box WO2)
    - Tarantelli, Ezio, 1975-1982, Folder 1 of 5 (Box WO2)
    - Tarantelli, Ezio, 1975-1982, Folders 2-5 of 5 (Box WO3)
    - Thulstrup, Jorn, 1983 (Box WO3)
    - Tobin, James, 1959-1981, Folders 1-5 of 7 folders (Box WO3)
    - Tobin, James, 1959-1981, Folders 6-7 of 7 folders (Box WO4)
    - Villacis, Jos, 1999 (Box WO4)
    - Wallace, Neil, 1984 Jan. (Box WO4)
  - Non-Academic Works Subseries, 1937-2003 and undated, bulk 1973-2003, 3 boxes
    Contains newspaper and magazine articles, editorials, op-ed pieces, and many other writings by Modigliani that are directed to a popular audience and are closely related to Modigliani's academic and political interests. Many of these pieces center on fiscal and economic policies of the United States and Italian governments, on politics and social conditions in those countries, and on the European economy. The contents of this subseries reveal the development of Modigliani's social and political sympathies over many decades, beginning in the 1970s and ending with his death in 2003. The earliest item dates from 1936, shortly before Modigliani left Italy for the U.S., and discusses the Fascist Party's economic policies. Some of the later editorial pieces stem from his membership with a group of economists against the arms race. Through his writings, Modigliani projects a clear and forceful voice on what he felt were the most challenging problems and injustices facing the modern world. Roughly half of the materials is in the Italian language. Arranged chronologically by date of publication.
    - By Franco Modigliani (Box NW1)
      - 1937, La funzione del Partito nel controllo dei prezzi (Box NW1)
      - 1947 Dec. 21 - Letter to the editor, New York Times (Box NW1)
      - 1970 Dec. 24, I Quattro Comandamenti (Box NW1)
      - 1972
        - Nov. 29, Tassazione giusta e pieno impiego le vie della prosperitá americana (Box NW1)
        - Dec. 20, Le complesse trattative per la riforma monetaria (Box NW1)
      - 1973
        - Jan. 10, Nel 1973 ci sará il 'boom' dell'economia americana (Box NW1)
        - Feb. 7, Vietnam e Wall Street (Box NW1)
        - Mar. 9, Gli speculatori della crisi monetaria (Box NW1)
        - Apr. 4, La Spagna rassomiglia all'Italia del 'boom' (Box NW1)
        - May 16, La qualitá della vita secondo l'Inghilterra (Box NW1)
        - June 13, Il ruolo degli economisti nella Svezia del benessere (Box NW1)
        - July 11, Bisogna ridare fiducia per combattere l'inflazione (Box NW1)
        - Aug. 4, Il punto sulla situazione dell'economia italiana (Box NW1)
        - Sept. 12, Una lezione dall'America sul controllo dei prezzi (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 28, Gli effetti dell'inflazione sul mercato delle abitazioni (Box NW1)
      - 1974
        - Jan. 6, I riflessi economici della crisi petrolifera (Box NW1)
        - Jan. 9, Alcuni dubbi sul nuovo 'modello di sviluppo' (Box NW1)
        - Jan. 24, 'Miopia' francese (Box NW1)
        - Jan. 26, Riformare il 'serpente' (Box NW1)
        - Feb. 3, Nel dubbio i prezzi saliranno (Box NW1)
        - Mar. 6, Una terapia contro la crisi (Box NW1)
      - 1975
        - Feb. 3, Attenzione ai pericoli della contingenza unificata (Box NW1)
        - Feb. 13, Gestione straordinaria per l'economia Usa (Box NW1)
        - Feb. 26, Tax Cut: Why It Must Be Quick and Big (Box NW1)
        - Feb.
          - Explaining the Administration's Economic Program, (unpublished) (Box NW1)
          - MIT Professor Urges High, Permanent Tax Cut (Box NW1)
        - Mar. 9, Se un operaio guadagnasse mezzo milione al mese (Box NW1)
      - 1976
        - Feb. 9, Support for Mr. Baffi (Box NW1)
        - Dec. 8, Se la barca affonda.... (Box NW1)
      - 1977 Nov. 6, Does M-1 Deserve All That Attention? (Box NW1)
      - 1978
        - Feb. 12, Risposta a Savona (Box NW1)
        - Dec. 1, Sistema monetario europeo: i pro e i contro per l'Italia (Box NW1)
      - 1981
        - Sept. 29, Questions About the Bottle Bill (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 25, Lo Stato e la scala mobile (Box NW1)
      - 1985
        - Mar. 23, Tartassati o esentati (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 3, And Why the Deficit Must be Slashed (Box NW1)
      - 1986
        - Apr. 28, An Import Tax Would Provide Relief for Oil States (Box NW1)
        - Dec., Answer to Paul M. French (Box NW1)
      - 1987
        - Feb., Manca la domanda perché anche negli altri paesi c'è disoccupazione? (Box NW1)
        - Mar. 1, In the Shadow of the Budget Deficit (Box NW1)
        - Apr. 28, Willing the Means for Europe's Jobs (Box NW1)
      - 1988, Piú fiducia nei 'futures' (Box NW1)
      - 1989
        - Jan. 3, Easing the Mexican Interest Burden (Box NW1)
        - Feb. 8, A Little Extra Leverage is No Call for Alarm (Box NW1)
        - Mar. 12, Cutting Deficit is Only Acceptable Course (Box NW1)
        - Apr. 23, Which Generation Should Foot the Bill? (Box NW1)
        - June 8, Science and the State: A U.S. View (Box NW1)
        - Oct. 17, Senza nuove regole e sempre periferia (Box NW1)
      - 1990
        - Jan. 7, Diventeremo piú ricchi? (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 2, Proposition 3 Ballot Question (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 19, Reforms Are Overdue (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 20, L'emigrazione della Borsa (Box NW1)
      - 1992 Sept. 6, Bush Takes Economics Beyond Voodoo (Box NW1)
      - 1993
        - Mar. 23, Nobelists Rate Clintonomics (Box NW1)
        - Apr. 6, Defending Macroeconomics (Box NW1)
        - May 5
          - Due consigli per il governo Ciampi (Box NW1)
          - The Year of the Great Opportunity (Box NW1)
        - May 13 - Letter to the editor, Financial Times (Box NW1)
        - June 4, Rewarding Subject for Study (Box NW1)
        - July 29, Why the EMS Deserves an Early Burial (Box NW1)
        - Aug. 6, No Reason to Mourn (Box NW1)
        - Aug. 18, Why Foot Dragging By Europe's Banks? (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 12, Ciampi, troppa prudenza (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 17, Fascist Coup Won't Take Root Here (Box NW1)
        - Nov. 24, Due anni per bloccare il debito (Box NW1)
        - Nov., A New Social Compact (Box NW1)
        - Nota per i colleghi italiani (Box NW1)
      - 1994
        - Jan. 23
          - Los sindicatos, responsables de la baja competitividad al exigir desmesurados aumentos salariales (Box NW1)
          - Spanish Unemployment: The Problem and Some Proposed Solutions (Box NW1)
        - Jan., Italian Budget Deficit to Disappear in 1994 (Box NW1)
        - Apr. 13, When Price Controls Benefit All (Box NW1)
        - Oct. 21, A Partial Cure for Italy's Deficit (Box NW1)
        - Dec. 27, Italian Coalition Didn't Fight Corruption (Box NW1)
        - Italian economic planning (Box NW2)
        - Passing the Generational Buck (Box NW2)
      - 1995
        - Jan. 27, Auguri, Italia la ricetta Dini quella giusta (Box NW2)
        - Feb. 18, Rigore e veri sacrifici per salvarci dal baratro (Box NW2)
        - Mar. 18, Le dimissioni con il 'nocciolino' (Box NW2)
        - May 14, L'emorragia della pensione (Box NW2)
        - Oct. 8, Manovra, tregua tra Dini e Fazio (Box NW2)
        - Oct. 20, A Virtuous Circle is the Key to Maastricht (Box NW2)
        - Oct. 25, I pugnali e la lira (Box NW2)
        - Oct. 28, Caro Martino, hai sbagliato il bersaglio (Box NW2)
        - Nov. 19, Le fondazioni? Ma molliamole (Box NW2)
      - 1996 - Unpublished letters to the editor, New York Times (Box NW2)
      - 1997
        - Mar. 14, A Euro Minus the D-Mark (Box NW2)
        - Aug., untitled - Debate between M. Draghi, E. Scalfari, and Ciampi (Box NW2)
        - Articles, editorials, and interviews in Italian press on social security in Europe (Box NW2)
      - 1998
        - Jan. 16, Perils of Unemployment (Box NW2)
        - Jan., Shareholder Value: Myth or Reality? (Box NW2)
        - Feb. 19, Fondi pensione complementari: motivazioni e critiche (Box NW2)
        - Mar. 7, Yes to the Euro, But Also to an Investment Plan for Jobs (Box NW2)
        - Apr. 14, Il debito italiano? Non fa paura (Box NW2)
        - Dec. 17, Ecco come cambiare le pensioni (Box NW2)
      - 1999
        - Apr. 3, Modigliani's Model (Box NW2)
        - May/June
          - Il futuro possibile (Box NW2)
          - Technologically Improved Plan Administration Will Enhance Retirement Savings (Box NW2)
        - Oct. 27, Risparmio utile solo se non dorme (Box NW2)
      - 2000
        - Sept. 1, Banchieri, burocrati ciechi (Box NW2)
        - Scienza economica e dinamica del reale (Box NW2)
      - 2001
        - Jan./Mar., Nuove prospettive previdenziali (Box NW2)
        - Apr. 9, America is Borrowing Trouble (Box NW2)
        - circa 2001 - Unpublished op-ed article, Business Week (Box NW2)
      - 2003
        - Jan./Mar., Un sistema previdenziale misto per un futuro delle casse professionali in Europa (Box NW2)
        - Mar. 12, Saving Social Security (Box NW2)
        - May 22, Dangers of the Dividend Tax Cut (Box NW2)
        - June, The Real Social Security Question (Box NW2)
        - Sept. 23, A Shocking Award to Berlusconi (Box NW2)
        - Sept. 28, Quando il risparmio faceva paura (Box NW2)
        - Sept. 29, Invest Social Security, but Don't Privatize (Box NW2)
        - Oct. - Ciampi/Modigliani in newspaper articles (Box NW2)
      - Undated
        - Articolo 1 per Sviluppo Quotidani (Box NW2)
        - La mia riforma delle pensioni (Box NW2)
    - By Others (Box NW3)
      - 1968
        - Mar. 22, Modigliani Analyzes World Gold Position (Box NW3)
        - Dec. 3, Modigliani Analyzes Monetary Crisis (Box NW3)
      - 1969 June 19, Dove va l'economia moderna? (Box NW3)
      - 1971 Dec., A More American Dollar (Box NW3)
      - 1975
        - Feb. 5, L'accordo sulla contingenza: nuovo intervento di La Malfa (Box NW3)
        - Feb. 24, $30 to $40 Billion Tax Cut Urged (Box NW3)
        - July 14, Critics Urge Fed to Hold Down Rates (Box NW3)
        - Oct. 14, Local Professors Protest Economists' Actions in Chile (Box NW3)
        - Oct. 24, Money Supply Climbs Sharply (Box NW3)
      - 1976
        - Sept. 18, Monetarist Reasoning Hit By Economist (Box NW3)
        - Sept. 20, Economists Sound Off on Boardwalk (Box NW3)
        - Sept. 21, Carter's Economy vs. Ford's: To Tune or Not to Tune (Box NW3)
        - Sept., We've Learned How to Lick Inflation (Box NW3)
        - Oct. 4, Democratic Economists Dust Off Their Activism (Box NW3)
      - 1978 Dec. 11, The U.S. Bias Against Saving Leads To.... (Box NW3)
      - 1979 Mar. 12, The Stock Market Should Be Twice As High As It Is (Box NW3)
      - 1980 Oct. 12, I paladini della triste scienza (Box NW3)
      - 1981
        - Nov. 4, Will History Repeat Itself? (Box NW3)
        - Dec. 7, Assets for Sale, Cheap; Investors Beware (Box NW3)
      - 1984, Schwartz on Modigliani (Box NW3)
      - 1985, Modigliani, Franco (1981- ), in Great Economists since Keynes (Box NW3)
      - 1986
        - Mar. 21, The 1985 Nobel Prize in Economics (Box NW3)
        - May 11, The Retirement Business: The Rules of the Game Are About to Change Again (Box NW3)
      - 1987
        - Oct. 22, The Balanced Budget Amendment (Box NW3)
        - Oct., Lights! Camera! Economists! (Box NW3)
        - Dec. 18, World Outlook: Warning Issued (Box NW3)
        - The Debate Over Stabilization Policy (Box NW3)
      - 1990
        - Dec. 8, Unlocking Corporate Finance (Box NW3)
        - Franco Modigliani, in A History of Economic Theory: Classic Contributions 1720-1980 (Box NW3)
      - 1991 Apr. 27, Intervento del Professor Mario Monti, Rettore dell'Universitá Bocconi in occasione del conferimento del 'Premio Internazionale Stivale d'Oro 1991...' (Box NW3)
      - 1994, How Are the Mighty Fallen: Rejected Classic Articles by Leading Economists (Box NW3)
      - 1995
        - Jan. 28, Caro Nobel, ti sbagli (Box NW3)
        - (Mar. 14?), Il trionfo del Laureato (Box NW3)
        - Mar. 31, 'Troppo tardi, il caos non finito' (Box NW3)
        - June 6
          - La riforma delle pensioni divide i Nobel Modigliani e Samuelson and two other articles (Box NW3)
          - Clippings from La Repubblica, Il Manifesto, Corriere della Sera, and Il Sole 24 Ore (Box NW3)
        - Aug. 25, Modigliani: brava Italia ritornata la fiducia (Box NW3)
        - Oct. 26, Caro Modigliani, lei rimasto a settant'anni fa (Box NW3)
      - 1997
        - May 12, Italy Wants the Euro But Does the Euro Want It? Rome Stung by Cool Reception.... (Box NW3)
        - May 27, Tax the Rich, Nuke the Poor (Box NW3)
      - 1998
        - Feb. 2, Can 27 Nobel Laureates Be Wrong? (Box NW3)
        - July 9, Le sovvenzioni non aiutano il Sud (Box NW3)
      - 2000
        - Mar. 31, Modigliani's Message: It's a Bubble, and Bubbles Will Burst (Box NW3)
        - Apr. 5
          - 'Beleid stimuleert werkloosheid': Nobelprijwinnaar beschuldigt ECB (Box NW3)
          - Piú difficile un divorzio che licenziare un operaio (Box NW3)
        - Apr. 6, Da Sabato Franco Modigliani sará cittadino onorario di Iseo (Box NW3)
        - Apr. 10, Un libro di La Malfa sui rischi dell'euro (Box NW3)
        - Apr. 11
          - Pensioni, Modigliani incontra le parti sociali (Box NW3)
          - Il governo arruola Modigliani ai sindicati non basta (Box NW3)
        - June 6, Meno tasse piú lavoro: La ricetta per creare occupazioni (Box NW3)
        - Sept. 12, Ford Joins MIT to Bring Nobel Laureates to the Institute (Box NW3)
        - Sept. 20, Nobel Prize-Winning Economists Share Insights, Make Predictions (Box NW3)
        - Nov., Franco Modigliani (Box NW3)
      - 2001
        - May 2, Rodrigo Rata habla en el Massachusetts Institute sobre el futuro del euro (Box NW3)
        - May 28, Italy: Can Berlusconi Renew the Nation? (Box NW3)
        - Sept. 17, Tisch, Modigliani Say Economic Life Goes On (Box NW3)
      - 2002
        - Feb. 22, Modigliani e il Tallone d'Achille del Tfr (Box NW3)
        - Nov., Articles from NOVA: Associazione Italiana MBA (Box NW3)
      - 2003 Sept. 23, A New York ebrei divisi sull'omaggio al premier italiano (Box NW3)
      - Undated, Per uscire dal tunnel (Box NW3)
- Professional Service Series, 1961-2002 and undated, 16 boxes
  Houses correspondence, minutes, transcripts of testimony, drafts of papers, reports, and other materials stemming from Modigliani's professional activities that he undertook in addition to his academic work. The series is organized into the following four subseries: Federal Reserve Board, Hearings and Testimony, International Economic Association, and Other Professional Service. Each of these subseries reveals the extent to which Modigliani committed his energies to these non-academic arenas.
  - Federal Reserve Board Subseries, 1964-1982 and undated
    Correspondence, memos, reports, drafts of papers, notes by Modigliani, printed materials and other materials related to three areas of activity sponsored by the U.S. Federal Reserve Board: the academic consultants meetings in which Modigliani participated extensively, along with other notable economists; discussions about improving the quality of the measured monetary aggregate, sponsored by the Committee on Monetary Statistics; and discussions on the reform of the discount window, around which Modigliani organized a seminar with other economists and presented his own views on this topic. Material on the MPS-FRB model is not located in this subseries, but rather in the Research and Writings Subseries of the Writings and Speeches Series. Arranged alphabetically by folder title and chronologically therein.
    - Academic consultants meeting, 1964 Jan. 30-1982 Sept. 30, folders 1-10 of 37 (Box PS1)
    - Academic consultants meeting, 1964 Jan. 30-1982 Sept. 30, folders 10-28 of 37 (Box PS2)
    - Academic consultants meeting, 1964 Jan. 30-1982 Sept. 30, folders 28-37 of 37 (Box PS3)
    - Committee on monetary statistics, 1974 Apr. 20-1978 Nov., folders 1-10 of 13 (Box PS4)
    - Committee on monetary statistics, 1974 Apr. 20-1978 Nov., folders 11-13 of 13 (Box PS5)
    - Reform of the discount window
      - Academic seminar, papers, 1966, 2 folders (Box PS5)
      - Academic seminar, proceedings, 1966, 2 folders (Box PS5)
      - Correspondence and notes, 1966-1968 (Box PS5)
      - Memorandum by Franco Modigliani, undated (Box PS5)
      - Printed materials and notes, 1966-1968, 2 folders (Box PS5)
  - Hearings and Testimony Subseries, 1961-2001
    Correspondence and transcriptions of hearings and testimony before the U.S. Congress or the European Parliament, in which Modigliani participated. Other supporting materials include memos, reports, and notes. The topics include government deficit and debt, inflation, indexed bonds, and social security. Arranged chronologically by date.
    - 1961 Dec., 2 folders (Box PS6)
    - 1962 July 9-13 (Box PS6)
    - 1968 May 8-9, 15-16, 2 folders (Box PS6)
    - 1971 July 20, 2 folders (Box PS6)
    - 1971 Aug. 16 (Box PS6)
    - Working paper, "The Demand for Index Bonds", 1974 Feb. 2 (Box PS6)
    - 1974 Feb. 7-8, 15, 18-22, 3 folders (Box PS6)
    - 1974 Sept. (Box PS6)
    - 1975 Feb. 14, 2 folders (Box PS7)
    - 1975 Feb. 25-26 (Box PS7)
    - 1975 Apr. 24, 2 folders (Box PS7)
    - 1975 Dec. 2-10, 2 folders (Box PS7)
    - Letter from Henry Reuss on Federal Reserve Reform Act of 1976, 1976 May 4 (Box PS7)
    - 1976 May 5, 2 folders (Box PS7)
    - 1977 Feb. 7, 2 folders (Box PS8)
    - 1978 Feb. 8 (Box PS8)
    - 1978 Feb. 22 (Box PS8)
    - 1978 Aug. 8 (Box PS8)
    - 1978 Dec. 14-15, 2 folders (Box PS8)
    - 1979 Feb. 6 (Box PS8)
    - 1982 Apr. 21, June 3 (Box PS8)
    - 1985 Oct. 21 (Box PS8)
    - 1987 Oct. 15 (Box PS8)
    - 1987 Oct. 15, Nov. 17-18 (Box PS8)
    - List of appearances before the Joint Economic Committee, 1968-1987, 1995 Aug. 1 (Box PS8)
    - 1999-2001 (Box PS8)
    - 2000 Apr. 4 (Box PS8)
  - International Economics Association Subseries, 1976-1983 and undated